

ANALYST

Details

Harare, Zimbabwe +263 781 164 639 erunesu7@gmail.com

Links

Portfolio

LinkedIn

Certificates

Skills

Microsoft Excel

Quickbooks

Alteryx

Python

Power BI, Tableau

Hobbies

Git

R, SQL

Writing , Reading,
Programming, Sound design

Languages

English

Shona

Profile

Insightful Business Intelligence Analyst and Economist with experience of working for an e-commerce start-up working to successfully analyse data and identify promising business opportunities and potential problems. Superior skills in Data Science, Machine Learning and Econometrics and the ability to effectively apply technical skills, economic theory and people skills.

Employment History

Research Data Scientist at DatBiz Analytics, Harare

DECEMBER 2022 — PRESENT

- Effectively seek client relationships with long term interest and advantage.
- Created and presented portfolios of growth, pointing out key trends.
- Perform thorough research and analysis on data and create reports on research activities.
- Merge data with existing data sets, careful to keep old data sets and documentation
- Utilize Python and R programming tools to build helpful predictive models.
- Provided a quantitative framework for evaluating and analysing alternative techniques.
- Brought forth a strong understanding of research methods and data analysis.

Data Analyst, Accounting Clerk at Zimboshop, Harare

DEC 2021 — NOVEMBER 2022

- Managed cashbook and reconciled accounts receivables and accounts payable records
- Worked to improve the overall performance of the systems by assessing billing, workflow, and customer relationship management and productivity.
- Led process-improvement focus groups as part of the initiative to achieve functional design within user systems.
- Guided efforts to improve technology systems in a real and cost effective way.
- · Worked well independently and also with others.
- Recommended and implemented changes that streamlined processes and improved usability.
- Brought forth excellent oral communication and interpersonal skills.
- Utilized superior data visualization and data management skills.
- During my time at Zimboshop, my work contributed to getting the company to an average of twenty-five thousand active customers each month in the first 3 months.

Education

Honours in Economic Science, University of Witwatersrand, Johannesburg

FEBRUARY 2020 — DECEMBER 2021

- Graduated with distinctions in Mathematical Economics, Financial Economics
- Awarded a distinction for my dissertation

Bachelor of Economic Science, University of Witwatersrand, Johannesburg

FEBRUARY 2017 — DECEMBER 2019

- Double major in Computational and Applied Mathematics
- Golden Key Student

Courses

Data Science and Machine Learning, CFI
Business Intelligence, CFI
Reading Financial Statements, CFI

Extra-curricular activities

Internships

Data Analysis and Visualizations at PwC Switzerland, Remote

MARCH 2022 — FEBRUARY 2023

- Merged data with existing data sets, careful to keep old data sets and documentation.
- Performed exploratory data analysis and discovered notable relationships.
- Utilized exploratory data analysis techniques to identify patterns, relationships, and trends.

Data Analytics at Accenture, Remote

JANUARY 2023 — FEBRUARY 2023

- Organized and analysed data and marketing results.
- Analysed data sets and helped companies make decisions based on findings.
- Performed exploratory data analysis and discovered notable relationships.
- Worked to assess the company's needs and resolve issues with the use of data.

References

References available upon request